Task Force on the Undergraduate Experience Records UA078
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
Task Force on the Undergraduate Experience Records
2001 -- 2003
1971 -- 2003
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
Task Force on the Undergraduate Experience
Bacow, Lawrence S.
Dean of Undergraduate Education
Dean of Undergraduate Admissions and Enrollment Management
UA078
1.2 Linear Feet 1 box
1 Digital Object(s) Zip file comprises 704 files, 330 of which represent preservation copies of originals that were converted to PDF.
68.2 Megabytes
Arrangement
This collection is organized in six series: Minutes; Correspondence; Reports-Task Force; Presentations and outreach; Reference; and Electronic files.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains reports, committee minutes, correspondence of the Task Force on the Undergraduate Experience.
Biographical / Historical
In the Fall of 2001, President Bacow created the Task Force on the Undergraduate Experience to evaluate both the strengths and weaknesses of the Tufts undergraduate experience and to assess how it might be enhanced for the 21st century. The final report was submitted in 2003.
Conditions Governing Access
University records are closed for 20 years from the date of their creation. Records older than 20 years that do not pertain to student education, staff and faculty employment and Board of Trustees records are open for research.
Administration and Governance -- Planning, evaluation, policies & procedures; Student life; Student Affairs and Services
- Minutes, 2002 -- 2003; UA078.001; 1.2 Linear Feet
  Scope and Contents
  This series consists of both hand written and typed minutes pertaining to the task force's meetings from 2002 - 2003. A comprehensive set of minutes are in series 6: electronic files.
  Arrangement
  This series is arranged in reverse chronological order.
  Conditions Governing Access
  20 years from date of creation.
  - Handwritten Meeting Minutes/ Notes, 2002 -- 2003; UA078.001.001.00001 (Box UA078 Shared 1)
  - Task Force Meeting Minutes, 2002 -- 2003; UA078.001.001.00002 (Box UA078 Shared 1)
- Correspondence, 2002 -- 2003; UA078.002; 1.2 Linear Feet
  This series contains print-outs of emails and attachments sent during 2002-2003. The correspondences and attachments are also in Series 6: electronic files.
  - Taskforce on the Undergraduate Experiance: Feedback from the Community; Spring, 2003; UA078.002.001.00003 (Box UA078 Shared 1)
  - Correspondence Received by the Task Force, 2002 -- 2003; UA078.002.001.00004 (Box UA078 Shared 1)
- Reports-Task Force, 2002 -- 2003; UA078.003; 1.2 Linear Feet
  This series includes reports and working documents produced by the Task Force during 2002 - 2003. The reports and documents are also in Series 6: electronic files.
  This series is arranged in mostly reversed chronological order.
  - Task Force on the Undergraduate Experience: Topical Reports (Drafts) from the Curriculum and Co-Curriculum Sub-Committees from July, 2002; UA078.003.001.00005 (Box UA078 Shared 1)
  - Task Force on the Undergraduate Experience: Faculty Survey 2002, UA078.003.001.00006 (Box UA078 Shared 1)
  - SAC Reports: Student Advisory Committee of Task Force, 2002 -- 2003; UA078.003.001.00007 (Box UA078 Shared 1)
  - Task Force Faculty Survey, 2002; UA078.003.001.00008 (Box UA078 Shared 1)
  - Task Force Reports, 2002 -- 2003; UA078.003.001.00009 (Box UA078 Shared 1)
  - Task Force Faculty Survey, 2002; UA078.003.001.00010 (Box UA078 Shared 1)
  - Task Force: Internal Reports and Working Documents, 2002 -- 2003; UA078.003.001.00011 (Box UA078 Shared 1)
  - More Task force Internal Reports - Working Documents, 2002 -- 2003; UA078.003.001.00012 (Box UA078 Shared 1)
- Presentations and Outreach, 2002 -- 2003; UA078.004; 1.2 Linear Feet
  This series contains presentation slides of their outreach to the community and the minutes of those outreach meetings during 2002 - 2003. The presentations and outreach minutes are also in Series 6: electronic files.
  - Task Force on the Undergraduate Experience: Community Outreach Meeting Minutes: Spring, 2003; UA078.004.001.00013 (Box UA078 Shared 1)
  - Task Force on the Undergraduate Experience: Community Outreach Meeting Minutes: Spring, 2002; UA078.004.001.00014 (Box UA078 Shared 1)
  - Task Force Presentations, 2002 -- 2003; UA078.004.001.00015 (Box UA078 Shared 1)
- Reference, 1971 -- 2003; UA078.005; 1.2 Linear Feet
  This series includes University Reports, reports by other Task Forces, and internal self studies between 1971 - 2003. The reference materials are also in Series 6: electronic files.
  This series is arranged in original order.
  - Tufts: The Total University in Changing Times- A Report to the President by the University Steering Committee, January, 1973; UA078.005.001.00016 (Box UA078 Shared 1)
  - Reports to Task Force from Misc. Tufts Committees, 2001 -- 2003; UA078.005.001.00017 (Box UA078 Shared 1)
  - Task Force Resource Lists, 2002; UA078.005.001.00018 (Box UA078 Shared 1)
  - Maxwell Report, 1982; UA078.005.001.00019 (Box UA078 Shared 1)
  - Campus Center- Phase 3, 1988; UA078.005.001.00020 (Box UA078 Shared 1)
  - Greek Life Initiative, 2002; UA078.005.001.00021 (Box UA078 Shared 1)
  - TF on Lesbian, Gay, Bisexual Issues, 1993; UA078.005.001.00022 (Box UA078 Shared 1)
  - Task Force on Race, 1997; UA078.005.001.00023 (Box UA078 Shared 1)
  - HEI, 1998; UA078.005.001.00024 (Box UA078 Shared 1)
  - Tufts: Strategic Plan, 1998; UA078.005.001.00025 (Box UA078 Shared 1)
  - Presidents Annual Report, 1971; UA078.005.001.00026 (Box UA078 Shared 1)
  - Report of Committee on Undergrad. Education, 1973; UA078.005.001.00027 (Box UA078 Shared 1)
  - Tufts 1992 Self Study, UA078.005.001.00028 (Box UA078 Shared 1)
  - Tufts 1997 5th yr Interim Report to NEASC, UA078.005.001.00029 (Box UA078 Shared 1)
  - Tufts Master Plan for Medford Campus, 1983; UA078.005.001.00030 (Box UA078 Shared 1)
- Electronic Files, 2002 -- 2003; UA078.006; 1 Digital Object(s) Zip file comprises 704 files, 330 of which represent preservation copies of originals that were converted to PDF.; 68.2 Megabytes
  This series contains all electronic documents and pictures created during 2002-2003 pertaining to the Task Force.
  This series is arranged alphabetically then chronologically. The hierarchy and arrangement of files is left in original order.
  - Electronic Files, 2002 -- 2003; UA078.006.002.00001; 1 Digital Object(s) Zip file comprises 704 files, 330 of which represent preservation copies of originals that were converted to PDF.; 68.2 Megabytes